I have been shot at multiple times in my
life for being protected yes okay that's
crazy we need to talk about that on
fairness
what okay that's that's some that's some
Virginia stuff right there
[Music]
gonna do the the stand back the little
little shimmy before we get into the
podcast episode get the blood flowing
yep I don't know man I feel like I'm
more tired than you and it's only 5 p.m
where I am
I don't know well yeah so I I've been
actually using this really interesting
app it's called time shifter and uh it's
supposed to help with jet lag adjustment
and so basically you tell it like what
flights you're gonna be taking and what
your sleep schedule normally is and then
it will tell you like a couple days
before like oh go to bed like two hours
later don't see sunlight don't drink
coffee and then like when you get there
like you should have told me this I for
the record for to clear up this
conversation uh Joel is currently in
Tokyo uh for the hacker one live hacking
event I will be leaving in about 12
hours to go to Tokyo so dude so this app
like it tells you how to beat jet lag is
that the vibe yeah I mean that's the
goal um they actually have like a
partnership with United so if you have a
1K membership you get like a free ear of
it or something
but uh even still it's like 25 bucks a
year it's like really not that bad
um and yeah it's been pretty interesting
it's you know if you've traveled a lot
it's not anything you're probably not
you know already aware of in terms of
like try to go to bed at a normal time
like just trying to like stay up and
take melatonin before you go to bed and
um the light I think is a really big
important thing because when you say
when you take light into your retinas it
uh it helps your circadian rhythm adjust
you're supposed to have light in the
morning and in the evening yeah and
that's one of the things that they
recommend and I noticed that helped
quite a bit of just like getting light
into my eyes and uh helping sort of just
reset myself about light in the morning
makes me think of that little that
little meme of the eagle you know like
going on the stupid mental stupid little
lock for my stupid mental and physical
you know what I'm talking about like
very relatable yeah okay I have to see
light uh yeah we need to we need to I
guess we need to get somebody to Overlay
that on the screen we should note that
down a little little people meme okay
yeah nice man well well uh how's the
how's the life hacking event going for
you we're not we're not team critical
thinking this time so I haven't caught
up with you at all how's it going yeah
yeah it's been pretty good um but it's
been a pretty hard target I'm not gonna
lie
um I found a couple things did some
collaborations with shubs so yeah we
found um you know we found one one
really interesting thing together but
it's been a pretty tough Target I'm not
gonna lie
um I think a lot of people I don't know
are we allowed to say who it is I know
it's kind of public the yes we are
allowed to say that the primary target
okay yeah so it's PayPal um so yeah I
know a lot of people there's a special
scope I'm not going to say what it is
um but there's a special scope and then
there's the PayPal scope and I know a
decent amount of people have actually
been focusing on the PayPal scope oh
really I know I was speaking with nagley
and nagley had some really interesting
stuff on the main scope for PayPal
um so yeah it's been it's been a really
interesting event I'm excited to see
what people are finding I haven't even
checked the lead report so I I wonder
how many bugs are in and stuff but uh I
think it's gonna be a cool event
yeah I think it's I think it's it's been
a little bit of a tricky one for me too
I've I've got a I think I've got a good
number of reports that I'm comfortable
with and happy with but it's just dupe
palooza because the the special skill
that they added for this one is like
just very very narrow and not extremely
featureful so uh you know you really
have to dig deep and you got to find
everything and uh yeah it's just I think
out of my 23 reports I think like
18 or 19 are duplicates including all of
my bugs above a high and above so I have
no maybe I might have one I might have
one solo High we'll see okay but uh my
the crit that I have or the two crits
that I have are all dupes and so just
like step to the heart damn well if it's
a crit we'll have to see I I was
speaking with Magdalena apparently
because of the way that this whole
account setup works and I think you know
what I'm talking about yeah they might
be doing privileges required low at
minimum for everything yeah so yeah
that's kinda
kind of annoying kind of frustrating
personally I don't think that it that
yeah I know they had some like special
stuff in the back end I think when we
were signing up to make it so we didn't
get flagged as spam so maybe that's why
you know you actually do need a little
bit of privileges required it's not as
simple as just like signing up for your
own account
um yeah but maybe we'll see we'll see at
the event man you know
not trying to you know toot my own horn
or anything here but your boy has some
persuasive skills and yeah okay put me
put me you can swing it for the whole
team yeah yeah that would be clutch
that'd be collapse cool
all right so we got a bunch of questions
I think that uh we're gonna go over yeah
yeah let's let's take a peep
um at these uh we're keep trying to keep
this episode pretty chill today since
Joel and I are both in the middle in the
throes of a live hacking event so we
went back and looked at uh Twitter post
from a while back when we were giving
away the kaido pro subscription
um and kind of grab some
questions off there for us to kind of
discuss
um let's do
let's go ahead and start with our boy
Jew Bob's uh and let's talk about
awesome does bug bounty hunting
unconditionally qualify as ethical
hacking do you think
so I think
I think you Bob's coming in with the
hard-hitting questions man
some serious questions
so the thing is when you call it bug
bounty hunting I think that
kind of implies at least the way that I
understand it that kind of implies that
you're hacking on a bug banning program
and to me when I think about it that way
that implies also that you are complying
with a program policy and so
theoretically most of the time it's
ethical hacking but I think we both know
that Safe Harbor isn't foolproof and
there are certainly edge cases and well
not even there are cases where you will
be going out of Safe Harbor if you you
know do certain things right so if you
do bug bounty hunting and you extort the
team that's not ethical hacking right
like asking for you know do this or I'm
going to release the data or I'm going
to keep it like yeah anything like that
I don't consider that ethical so I think
there there are certainly lines that you
can cross to make it non-ethical but
from like a baseline standpoint just
reporting a bug tube to a bug writing
program that's absolutely ethical in my
opinion
so
have a little bit of a
doctor because it also kind of toes the
boundary of what I was talking about
last week which was it's it's not our
responsibility to define a company's
threat model for them but I would feel a
little bit yucky about reporting
something that is that the company
wanted to receive that I know full and
well is technically impossible to
exploit
so I I've got a good example of this
okay so let's say
um I got a bunch of I don't know why
lately but I I get a bunch of DMS and
lately a lot of people have been asking
about
um Access Control origin star header
right uh you know access with uh you
know a asterisk origin plus
credentials exactly plus the access
control allow credentials true header
those two okay two things together
theoretically what this what should
happen with this is that you're allowed
to send cookies and then any origin let
is allowed to read the response right
but goals Divine yeah the the people
that defined the spec
thought hey this is dumb we shouldn't
allow them this to happen
um and uh and they said hey this is this
is not going to be exploited we're not
we're not going to make this you can't
use the Access Control credentials true
with the asterisk origin
um and so uh you know people are
messaging me like Hey how do I exploit
this and I'm telling them hey this is
not exploitable even though it's clearly
a misconfiguration like those headers
cannot be working together you know well
they just don't work together it causes
an error yeah so um you know if you were
to report that right and the team were
to accept it and you know that the team
accepts that let's say you you reported
it when you didn't know whether it was a
bug or not and the team accepted it and
paid it out then you found another one
but you now you know that it is not
it is not an exploitable bug
is that ethical hacking or not because
you're deceiving the company into paying
you um
what do you think so further from like a
program perspective the way that I would
view this is that
well for one it would be hard to pay
that out except for like a low or maybe
a low end of medium and the reason for
that is that you shouldn't pay it out at
all well yeah I mean so well here's why
I might consider paying it and the
reason is that it's a security
configuration right and so the reality
is that like is something wrong yes
is it exploitable right now
no would it be exploitable in certain
edge cases potentially right like maybe
you could export it in an older browser
or uh like certain browser I don't know
right like there might be certain edge
cases where it's where it's possible and
I think the fact that it's there and
written and show like all it takes is
one slip up for that to go wrong
um but it's not exploitable right like
like you said and so I think that is a
huge mitigating factor that like almost
nullifies your Bounty essentially
because what's the security impact
nothing but what's the security issue
something and so I think it's kind of
Towing the line between a bug and not a
bug I could see like 50 50 whether or
not the program wants to accept it or
not yeah yeah I mean I would I think
it's ethical
it's ethical even though even though you
know that there is no possible way for
it to be exploited
I think the ethics are the same for the
program as it is for the reporter
whether or not they want to accept it
and pay it out or like if the program
says I'm not going to accept this that's
kind of the same ethical decision in my
mind as the reporter reporting it again
even though it's not exploitable
because not the program is accepting
well the program is accepting something
that's not valid and the research is
submitting something that's not valid
but the program in this scenario the
program doesn't know that right the
program doesn't know okay that's a
that's a big caveat if the if the
program doesn't know that it's not
exploitable well first of all
that's a problem
right like history I should see this and
be like I can't exploit this and it
probably should never even make it to
the team if the team it either doesn't
have triage or they decide to accept it
anyways that uh
um if they don't mention any like I feel
like somebody should mention it here's
another here's another Fringe case right
let's say you have an injection of a URL
of a JavaScript URL into an an a tag
with the uh Target blank attribute set
right and somebody clicks that link it
won't trigger in the browser because uh
you cannot trigger JavaScript URLs on on
uh underscore blank Target blank um
HTML tags I couldn't get that out yeah
um and so you know that's not
exploitable but like you said they're
one deleting one attribute away from an
xss but you know that that's not not you
know exploitable so is it ethical for
you to report that or not
so I think that is a little more of a
clear-cut case in my mind than the
headers because the headers are very
explicitly like you're setting a header
in your response this is configured it
correctly the fact that
just like being able to put a URL in an
element but that's not exploitable
I don't well yeah I don't know I'm going
back and forth
well I guess I guess yeah in order to in
order to Devil's Advocate my own point
right I guess I would say that there's
nothing really
there's nothing unethical about seeing
whether something meets the criteria
that a company has for their threat
model
um for their organization right and and
I guess it it definitely has to be uh I
think the rub is where how you describe
the issue in your report right like are
you saying hey
you know click this link and you'll get
an xss and then you actually don't and
you're like oh some browser restriction
bloody bloody blah should work in other
browsers bloody bloody blah or are you
saying like hey this isn't exploitable
in any active browsers but I thought you
might want to know because you guys are
very close to making a bad mistake
right and I think transfer transparency
is like the biggest thing here from both
sides yeah and so like as a researcher
if this is something you're going to
report
be ready for the program to not accept
it like just you know test the waters
though I think that like what what you
suggested there is a good idea submit it
see how they react see if this is
something they care about some some
security teams care about
misconfigurations like this a lot and
they'll accept it and they'll pay it
yeah um and like a security issue is a
security issue even if it's not fully
exploitable
I respect that
um you know but I think it's really up
to each program to decide how they want
to handle that and if it's something
they want to say sorry this is an
informative
um and then they fix it I also don't
really have a problem with that because
in most like if in most cases if you
reported something new bug body program
I could understand you getting
frustrated if they they closed it and
then they fixed it anyways but this is
not exploitable and so it's really more
just you're letting them know that this
is a thing yeah and if they want to like
toss you some points or like you know a
small bonus Bounty or swag or something
like that I think that's more than
reasonable depending on again depending
on the program but there's not really a
great clear-cut case a little bit I'm a
little bit uh it's a little bit
interesting to hear you talk about uh
maybe potentially maybe paying bounties
for things that are not fully
exploitable I uh might have to give uh
your program a try sometime now I'm
gonna have to go and look at all the
security misconfiguration no you're good
man
um yeah jubabs thanks for the question
man I think that that's a that's a good
one and um the only other scenario that
kind of pops into my head about whether
or not
uh like it's ethical for for us to
participate in a bug Bounty program in
all scenarios is this case of lying
about severity as well
um
we have a friend I think you know what
friend I'm talking about
that
that it always like just goes very I'm
not sure I'm not saying he's lying about
the I'm sorry they're lying about the uh
the severity of the bug
um but like it's definitely strongly
worded right and I have a little bit of
an ethical thing about this because at
the end of the day like the people on on
the triagers on on the security teams
and stuff like that they're seeing a lot
of reports you know
um oftentimes they're they're not the
ones that are also doing the offensive
hacking right so they're not as you know
intimately familiar with the details of
um the boundaries of all these bugs and
so you know pulling a fast one on these
guys to gain a buck or two is I think
unethical so yeah unethical
yeah yeah unethical yeah I think um
I think everybody especially people who
hack a lot and like full-time and that
kind of stuff this is a really tricky
and easy
hole to fall into because when you're
submitting stuff
like you don't really want to you know
toot your own horn too much but at the
same time you also want to like
you know critical information being
leaked like you know you want to sell it
I mean you gotta you want to get your
report attention you know
exactly so like I think there's a line
between like you want to to be like this
is like to demonstrate that there's
impact here so the team doesn't under
play it but also
you know you don't really want to be
like you know I don't I don't like lying
to programs but I don't think like I
think if you have to lie and you're like
being dishonest like that's kind of
where I draw my personal ethical
boundary of like where is this ethical
hacking and like where is this not
ethical hacking um
and the reality is that if the like
triage is in the programs and everybody
is doing their job properly and they
read through the report properly they
should see through that still and they
should pay it appropriately and if you
as the hacker have a problem with that
that's not really the programs well I I
also think here's another here's another
scenario that I've kind of felt a little
ethical quandary on before is like
I don't know man like
clearly this is not an ethical problem
but I feel really bad about sometimes
not all the time but sometimes I feel
bad about reporting bugs that will just
clearly never ever ever ever ever ever
ever ever be exploited like like and
they are bugs and they're valid you know
let's say access control bypasses or
whatever but like I cannot even fathom a
world in which some attacker would be
like I'm gonna like unsubscribe you from
these email notifications you know like
you know like to try to get too deeper
about this because
I mean you can really extend this to LIT
like every small program and be like
who's even using this thing like oh no
that's true but you know but I think
like you know A Bug's a bug
you know
Bugatti is kind of a game yeah we've
talked about this there's a lot of meta
aspect to
how you report stuff and all that kind
of stuff so I I don't know it's a it's a
very tricky it is true um it's a very
tricky line to to figure out where that
is and how you should be reporting stuff
and what's ethical and what's not
ethical and all that kind of stuff so
yeah I don't know yeah okay so scope
right that's the other thing that you
Bob mentioned in their comment
um
is it ethical to go out of scope to
attack an in-scope asset
okay so actually I'll take first take on
that one while you think
um I'm gonna say no and the reason for
that is that
it's technically illegal
um and and so even though you're you
have Goodwill and you have good intent
and you know you're not gonna you know
weaponize these vulnerabilities to
attack anyone else
uh the fact that you are hacking A
system that you are not authorized to
hack that crosses an ethical boundary
that that it's kind of like to me it's
kind of like trespassing right like you
you you're not gonna you know break
anybody's house or like you know cut
down somebody's trees or something but
if you're walking through their property
for uh you know a period of time that's
it's not hurting anybody so to speak but
it is technically illegal
um and that's why I would say going out
of scope uh is not is not a good not a
good practice and and I think there are
some scenarios where I I will say I've
seen programs do this sometimes where
they'll say hey
um star.site.com is uh is in scope but
not eligible for bounties
um and then and then but you know
www.site.com is eligible for bounties
and in those scenarios since it's
technically in scope you can hack on
that all you want and then try to use
that to affect www I think that's a
really good configuration
yeah um this is one of those really
tricky cases and again this is going to
be program by program
um
it's just you know
okay I'm pretty proud of that
trespassing analogy too yeah
yeah like I think that's a great analogy
like man it's so hard because like I
think all programs should be paying for
impact right and
yeah that means that going out of scope
to provide impact on the main scope
is still impact on the main scope
however just like you said it's going
out of scope and that by definition is
like violating the program terms and
like doing things that you shouldn't be
doing and so
you know it's again it's kind of one of
those cases where if you submit
something like this don't be surprised
that the program's like hell no this is
absolutely not we're not going to accept
this like this you know and you
shouldn't have done that and you're
lucky we're not Banning you right like I
think that like the program has every
right to be frustrated and mad if you do
that on the other hand
impact is impact and if you control some
really solid like if it's a critical I I
think it's a security team I would have
a hard time being mad if it was a third
party because it's critical like if you
can provide critical impact to my
program even if it's a third party
one of the things you have to realize as
a security program is that the
relationships that you have with your
third parties and the way that you
handle accounts and data and all that
kind of stuff sharing with third parties
is your responsibility as a security
team it's not just like oh so that's the
third party now like like we're you know
totally wipes clean of our liability
here no like your you know data and
whatever is still involved there so you
should still own that to some extent but
this I think goes back a little bit to
like the whole
zero day like should you report a zero
Day to a program and that kind of stuff
and where's the responsibility lie for
Bounty and should they pay for it and
all that kind of stuff and like
it's a very tricky scenario like I think
at the end of the day the security team
is still probably going to reach out to
that third party and they're gonna get
it fixed and they're gonna figure out
how to fix it from their side so that
it's not creating that impact on the
main program or on the main scope yeah
but as a hacker you are definitely
Crossing some lines there and you're
opening yourself up to some Risk by
going out of scope and reporting
something that's out of scope and
explicitly you know kind of violating
some some boundaries and some rules in
order to get that critical okay so yes I
hear that and it actually makes me think
of a better analogy for the oh okay okay
so this time I'll take my no trespassing
signs this time we're trespassing right
but we're doing we'll put it back up
we're doing it to save a cat
actually actually I told you that I'm no
longer allergic to cats right
uh yes apparently dude I I am I'm free
of my lifelong allergy to cats and I pet
a cat for the first time in my life the
other day and it was like so crazy it
was lit man anyway so I'm gonna put it
back to a cat we're trespassing on the
property but we're doing so to save a
cat right okay how does that feel right
like that feels that feels
okay maybe even even more accurate would
be we're trespassing on a property
looking for a person's lost cat right
because because at the end of the day
when we're bug hunting we don't know
that we're gonna find a bug but if we do
find a bug we are helping that that that
program we are finding that person's cat
um sure and I'm gonna use an America
analogy here okay so
in America if you were to do this
yes exactly that's exactly where I was
going 50 50 chance right like that
homeowner has every right you're on
their property or on private property
you're trespassing like you didn't ask
permission don't live in America it's
not actually a 50 50 chance but there is
definitely a non-zero chance that you'll
be shot at I have been shot at multiple
times in my life for being protected yes
okay that's crazy yeah we need to talk
about that unfair holy cow
what okay that's that's some that's some
Virginia stuff right there right there
for sure
um but yeah no I think like
okay in the same way that like the
homeowner or whatever has the right to
defend their property and like tell you
to get get the hell out of there same
thing for the program right like they
have the right to say this is not in
scope
We're Not Gonna accept this get the hell
off my property right right exactly yeah
and um you know as a researcher don't be
surprised if that happens that's kind of
the risk that you're accepting by
submitting that stuff so yeah
um
yeah I don't know I think
you can't play stupid in these in these
situations as a researcher like you
don't you definitely know what you're
doing like if you're going out of scope
and you're writing up that report you
know like there's a risk that they're
gonna say no or they're gonna get mad
about that and you know you have a good
relationship with the program or
hopefully it's a it's a program that is
willing to look past that uh but you
know there's always going to be the
chance of mitigating factors or uh not
accepting it or marking it as n a or
informative and still fixing it on the
back end you know those are things that
happens I will say as well that um
there are some
I guess caveats being made in computer
Fraud and Abuse Act laws
for good faith security research and so
I haven't really gone down the rabbit
hole lately of what that actually looks
like and especially for like people like
us who have an established record of of
ethical hacking I'm not sure if going
out of scope would technically be
illegal
um and if it if it if it is then that
ethical boundary is still there but if
it's not then yeah that's not yeah I
forget what the exact wording is it's
either best intent or good face it's a
security research or something like that
I think in terms of legality now the
reality let's get into the weeds a
little bit they are they didn't actually
change the CFA the justice department
made a statement that said this is how
you should prosecute the cfaa so
if you're adhering to you know best
intent and good faith ethical hacking
then that shouldn't be illegal according
to this gfaa and it shouldn't be charged
but
I think that's separate from bug Bounty
right like in terms of Ethics like
you're everybody's ethics are different
in terms of legality it's probably legal
or less at least in the US and in terms
of validity for eligibility for a bounty
well um
to do something illegal
well that's a personal choice
cool
cool screwing around so I'm going to
tell you the story about me getting shot
at because it's pretty it's a pretty
great story okay so I grew up in
Virginia and like
a couple hundred yards now it's probably
like a mile actually
um behind my house there was this really
awesome waterfall like 20-foot waterfall
um okay massive waterfall built by
slaves in the Civil War and uh oh and
pretty cool and so it was had like you
know it was flowing water a very
beautiful area but it was on somebody
else's property and and so uh but it was
very far from their house right like
okay you know and like you could barely
see their house in the distance right so
I so it's on their property it is
definitely on their property yeah okay
so uh so you know being the kid that I
am I've snuck out there a couple times
and you know enjoyed the beautiful how
old were you at this point okay hold on
like let's let's let's let's hold off on
that one
um so we
when I was a kid I used to go out there
often right so but this time that I'm
talking about that I got shot at I was I
was a teenager let's just say you know
not a a young teenager and
um I was going to go on a picnic with my
girlfriend
uh and so my girlfriend and I were
walking you know through the woods I had
made like this little like basket and it
was all cute and everything and we're
like you know walking to the waterfall
it's gonna be so fun and then
um all of a sudden I just hear shots
ringing out over our head holy [__] and
and I look across the lake and I see
like very very far away I mean the
person is like this small at this point
but they're standing on their Deck with
a gun
and we just like book it that back the
other way and move our picnic to the
middle of the woods that was on my
property I was you still did the picnic
oh yeah we did the picnic we're not
about to let it good you know him
sandwich go to waste no sir
still was hungry man
um so that's awesome yeah
critical thinking episode but you know
such as what a while the little
childhood experience there holy cow it's
kind of crazy
um all right let's see if there's any of
these any other
um
questions on here that looked good
you could you could run them through
real quick how to set up a mobile
intercept proxy that kind of I feel like
that kind of yeah yeah just talk them
through that real quick while I figure
out some other stuff
yeah so typically what I do regardless
of whether or not it's an emulator or a
physical device
um if it's a physical device plug it in
but either way you just want it to show
up on ADB and have debugging enabled and
then from there you just do ADB reverse
TCP colon 8080 TCP colon 8080 and what
that will do is it creates a tunnel
between your host and the device
um on port 8080 and so that means that
any traffic that's going to port 8080 on
the device will get tunneled to port
8080 on your host machine and that's
seriously the easiest like most
straightforward foolproof way that I've
found to proxy you don't have to worry
about Network conditions you don't have
to proxy to an IP address you literally
proxy to
127.001 port 8080 it goes over ADB it
tunnels and there's no connectivity
concerns or anything like that it's it's
great
so so then you just go into the mobile
app
um or the the mobile device's uh Wi-Fi
settings yeah the Wi-Fi settings set up
the the proxy to point at localhost 8080
yeah just edit your network proxy manual
host 127001 port 8080 and yeah it should
work that easy you should be able to you
know just navigate to like burp in your
browser if you want to get the ca cert
um all that stuff should just work so
yeah and then and then the easiest way
to download the casert like you said is
just hit uh localhost 8080 they'll see
you'll see a little CA cert uh button up
at the top right hand corner on the burp
click that download the search sometimes
you have to rename it to dots yeah CRT
yeah or CRT yeah yeah either of those
from der and then you just go into your
security settings trusted trusted
credentials CA certificates install one
and uh you just select it from your SD
card and then it's good to go that's the
easy part though because most
applications are implementing cert
pinning so for that you're gonna need
some some
which we talked about I believe on what
was that episode that was an early one I
think I think it was like 12 12 14 12 or
14. I'm gonna pull it up right now
uh yeah yeah boy remembers numbers man
yeah uh what was LA Live hacking is that
12 was J haddocks uh okay yeah you got
this better than I do LA Live hacking
was 17. oh okay wow I'm way off
cool but yeah no it's that easy
um you know very straightforward and uh
I think during the mobile episode we
actually talked about the freedom
pinning I have a universal quote unquote
Universal um on pitting scripts uh that
is linked there and that works like 98
of the time for me you can link that in
the description as well
Eagle Eagle Meme and then uh sir
pinning script okay so
um
so next topic that I so I kind of
scrolled through these I'm not gonna lie
dude there wasn't a lot of great
questions so come on critical thinking
listeners give us something deep like
there there there's a bunch of people
say critically God could you just think
like think critical okay
um uh so one of the ones that kept on
popping up was how do you
how do you approach a new Target what's
the first stuff you look at what's your
process and what kind of steps do you do
before you start hacking
um and I wish that we could give you a
recipe but there's not really a recipe
so um it really depends on the target uh
for me a lot of the time I try to figure
out what the app is and how to use it
like a human
um and so for me that often means
logging into the application navigating
around reading documentation
um kind of keeping a general eye on the
architecture of the application uh
trying to understand whether it's like a
single page app uh or whether you know
you've got they're using a front-end
framework like react or view what their
back end looks like are there a bunch of
different apis or their microservices
their graphql that sort of thing
um
I also look at auth a decent bit so
um at oauth at the two-factor
authentication flow
um
any sort of alternative authentication
paths like uh like like one-time
password being sent to your email you
know and you just click kind of click
that link and it logs you in like slack
does
um those sort of things are are um are
pretty
pretty pivotal to my methodology but it
it very much varies uh with every single
Target
yeah for me so I think there's a couple
like core steps that I like to follow
and it generally depends on like where
I'm at within the process of looking at
that Target so when I'm starting out
like from the very beginning a lot of it
is like what you said it's figuring out
what is this app what is it supposed to
do where where are sort of like the
natural boundaries in terms of uh what
functionality should be where are their
access controls kind of identifying
those no's like uh like Archangel yes
speaking about in the last episode
um and then from there if they have a
mobile app
um a lot of times I'll be looking at
that and just see what activities they
have exposed what are the intent filters
what what kind of functionality exists
from like an external attack surface
perspective on this on this app is there
any like weird JavaScript interfaces any
web views any content providers any of
that kind of stuff
um and I'll usually do a bit of a deep
dive on the mobile app and just like see
if there's any funky stuff that I should
be poking at and trying to exploit if I
don't really find anything there one of
the things I do like to do is look for
API endpoints within the mobile app and
just see is it different from the if
there's like a web app assuming that is
it different from that what is the auth
structure look like how do you log in
through the mobile app all that kind of
stuff
and then if I'm kind of hitting like a
wall I'd like to
split and sort of do Recon or do like
more breadth searching trying to find
new yeah yeah like what services exist
sub domains things that are in scope
that I haven't looked at that I might
not know about are there any weird URLs
or things that are provided in API
responses from the mobile app or from
the web app that I haven't looked at
um those are the types of things that I
want to take you know a little bit of a
closer look at and see if there's some
bugs that I haven't found or that I you
know might be easy wins um and then I
kind of just repeat that like you know
look for something find something figure
out what the functionality is dig if you
run out of things to dig at
try and move laterally find some other
you know or horizontally or whatever and
try and find new things to look at and
you know rinse and repeat kind of
grasping for for straws right now man
with this application that we're hacking
because it's like the scope is so small
and I've and I've exhausted all of it
you know all of the attack vectors that
I can think of over the past week
um you know I've tried them uh and yeah
and so I'm really kind of going back
over reiterating
um I'm reaching reaching for some really
crazy bugs and like tangentially related
third-party libraries that could result
in vulnerabilities
um yeah so it's it's definitely that's
definitely a part of the grind is
learning how to push through those
scenarios when you're like uh I'm out of
attack vectors but yeah oftentimes it's
a really tricky good stuff
I mean for me like especially for this
event like the way that they have the
scope structured has made it very
difficult for me to like
want to submit is everything I get you
know what I mean like I'll I'll find
something to be like oh that's kind of
interesting but I don't even want to
like dig into it because it'll be on
like a domain that's either explicitly
listed as ineligible for Bounty or it's
not in scope like the way that they have
the scope structure right you know I
don't know if you're looking at it but
it's very particular yeah and so that
has really limited the hacking that I've
chosen to do for this event and I think
I'm kind of holding myself back here a
little bit because of that but we should
compare notes on that after this because
I think there are some ways around a lot
of that because of what you kind of
mentioned before about like having
impact to the main domain and and PayPal
is really is really good about that if
you can show impact you know
um to to the primary application to the
primary target then I think you've got I
think you've got some good some good
bones there okay cool yeah let's compare
notes yeah for sure
um
sweet uh
yeah what so this next one was what what
kind of steps did you take before you
start hacking I think I think the only
other thing I wanted to add to this one
was
[Music]
um
like really we talk about this all the
time but like I get so much out of
reading documentation and it's going to
be dry at first and you know you're
gonna sit there and you're gonna be like
why am I reading this uh but re read the
main apps documentation and read the
developer portal documentation because
that's going to give you so much insight
into the application and actually I
missed multiple very critical bugs at
this live hacking event because I didn't
read literally every single page of the
of the developer uh section
um and had I had I read it I would have
absolutely found them uh but I missed it
so sucks man it sucks
um all right so uh before we bounce I've
got three little three little things
three little cool things and then I
guess we can also we're also going to go
over the reports weren't we
yeah yeah okay
um so I'll make these quick uh all right
number one uh two tweets from your boy
Rhino reader uh I just wanted to shout
these out because these are kind of
surprising to me that some of these that
when you introduced that was like as if
it was a guest but it's just me
you're like from from this awesome from
the Moon heard of hacker before the
legend me me no
um uh you know so here's the thing man
like I'm sure you get this all the time
as well but like I get tagged in like
five to ten Twitter posts a day and I
get saying like hey Ryan reader and then
like spam a bunch of other popular book
value hackers
um how do I exploit this thing right and
I try to respond to them if I can
um and so last last uh I guess two weeks
ago almost now somebody was like hey I
found an open redirect but it only
allows Google and target.com not other
websites what should I do how can I
exploit this and so I commented on it
because I knew the answer and the answer
is Google has a built-in open redirect
that uh they don't patch that is just a
part of functionality for Google and
that is google.com
amp slash S and then your target domain
um and so uh it's just funny because
does that work on mobile I believe it
does yes uh because normally amp Pages
like I that behavior is typically
restricted to Mobile so I'm curious if
it behaves a little bit differently if
you have like a mobile user agent and
stuff that's um we can uh
delete that real quick
yeah for those who don't know amp pages
are essentially no they're supposed to
be like mobile for okay yeah there you
go so it doesn't do that
yeah so mobile typically the way that
this works is that there's these amp
pages I forget what it what it like
stands for but it's it's meant to be
basically mobile friendly versions of
pages you see it a lot with uh news
websites especially pages
yeah yeah so it's really meant to be
like a simplified mobile-friendly
version of whatever page you're looking
at again I see it a lot with
um journalism and news websites like art
news articles and stuff uh but typically
if you try and visit an amp URL on
desktop it does what you said it
redirects you so that's probably why
that's happening is that it detects your
own mobile and it goes oh let me try and
render an actual amp page and if you're
on desktop it goes ah go back to the
main page oh very interesting Joel uh I
didn't know that that that's helpful to
know why that actually works
um yeah yeah so that if you're looking
for a chain for your open redirects
that's the one it was really funny
because like they like this guy tagged
me in this post I commented on it and
then like that comment got more retweets
and likes than like my normal Twitter
posts I was like wait a second what the
hell is going on here uh that's a good
one though that's a really that's a
really clever attack scenario especially
for like desktop clients yeah yeah
cool the other thing was I was
exploiting an exercise the other day
tweeted about it so uh if you guys
haven't seen that you can go check it
out but
um I just wanted to mention it on the
pot as well because it's a nice little
tidbit
um I was getting sort of uh stopped by
the X content type options no sniff
header when I was trying to change a
crlf into an xss so you know you're
you're adding the the break then you're
adding the content body you're providing
content length that sort of thing
um but uh for some reason I couldn't I I
in the scenario the content type header
had to be blank uh or else it would it
would break it
um and if you try to do if you do
content type blank it's going to try to
sniff it normally but uh in in the
scenario they had the no sniff header so
so uh I actually added another no sniff
header with an invalid value and if you
have two no sniff content type option
headers uh in one of them with an
invalid value one of them with a valid
value Chrome just throws the whole thing
out the window and yeah I was going to
say like potentially for the even just
for the content type providing two
values of it one should I mean that
leads to some kind of unanticipated
behavior with how it's going to behave
so
yeah yeah it definitely does and the
reason we couldn't overwrite the content
type was because the the uh crlf was in
the path and you couldn't put a slash in
it so you can't do HT you know text HTML
right so we couldn't override the
content type to to be a text uh an HTML
content type we tried everything we
could think of for that you have to have
a slash so we said all right what about
a blank content type and then she was
moving and that's how we got how we
popped it but I was just really
surprised to see the X content type
options uh header if you provide two of
them it's just like you know what
actually we just give up we don't know
what to do and then it just yeah it also
surprised at us from a client side like
yeah you'd think that would be more of
just like a server side control that
would you know do that if it didn't
detect something or you know yeah well
it's the browsers you know the header is
the response header is for the browsers
uh you know it tells the browsers
whether to sniff or not to sniff
um and so uh Chrome just said oh oh so
this is an
yeah oh okay I thought you meant in like
an outbound request that you were
changing the requests we're injecting
another X content type options header uh
in the response in trying to trigger the
xss and uh and the browser says all
right I'll sniff that if you give them
uh awesome
um
we're getting silly and this is what
happens when you stare at a screen for
12 hours a day
um okay last little one
this is actually a trick I use to to get
an ATO uh uh at uh let's just say
recently
um and uh and at recently recently
shut up
um uh so essentially
this scenario was a scenario you we
really often see which is uh you've got
a application that is using uh like
axios uh JS library on the on the front
end to communicate with an API and
they're authorizing it they're
authenticating into API by an
authorization Bearer header and that
header is just sort of stored in the
JavaScript State and not stored in local
storage or in a cookie right so can you
get an xss normally you're gonna you're
gonna try to pull your session token out
of
um local storage or out of a cookie
um right but in this scenario you can't
because it's not stored there so your
option is you can go through the oauth
flow which in this scenario had a bunch
of like
crazy intricacies with crypto stuff uh
to it like you had to generate like a
certain length nonce or whatever and
then it had to get past it was kind of a
pain in the butt
um so what I actually did was
I created an iframe uh to the same to
same origin page
um and then that iframe when it loaded
up it was going to try to reach out to
the API to load data and I just reached
into that iframe and overwrote the uh
fetch
uh function the window.fetch and I I
just put my own function in there I
shimmed it is what it's called and uh
essentially said okay anytime they call
fetch call my function and then and then
call Fetch and if that function call has
the authorization Bearer header in it
then Excel it to the attacker server so
it's not a crazy hack but it is
something to know that that is useful
um if you are trying to you know if you
have xss you have the opportunity to
overwrite functions like like fetch or
other properties
um within the uh within the window
um not all properties can be overwritten
but most of them can and you can use
that to save yourself some time and and
when proving an exploit or and sometimes
in some cases like JavaScript sandboxes
you can actually use these to escape the
sandbox and uh and get arbitrary.js
execution
that's super interesting I'm I'm curious
how it how it's stored in a place where
it's inex where it's not in local
storage and not in cookies but
would like shouldn't it always be
accessible from JavaScript if it's being
I'm sure it is said I I'm sure you know
I could hit like window dot like react
State because somehow it's setting it in
axios yeah yeah it is and it's from
within their like you know minified hell
that is you know whatever JavaScript
library they were using in the front end
um and so I just didn't feel like
freaking traversing the whole you know
JavaScript it's easier to set your own
function to to find that uh and it took
literally like two minutes to write the
exploit and uh pulled it out real easy
rather than having to do like an oauth
you know hijack this like oauth flow and
like generate a cryptographically
accurate you know novels or whatever so
I figured I'd mention it because it's a
cool little trick it's it's actually
unfortunately like the coolest thing
I've done this live hacking event
because all of the bugs have been Mega
boring they've been like you know well
actually I won't say what kind of bugs
they
um uh you know they they have not been
very interesting plugs so yeah congrats
to the PayPal team you don't have a lot
of you know crazy interesting bugs just
boring ones
good guys for having 40 bucks yeah yeah
cool
um is it do uh should I talk about my
the bug that I have oh yeah yeah let's
go ahead and go over some bugs that's
always cool it's always a dub
yeah so I had um I had a really
interesting bug a couple weeks ago um
and I I had talked to you about this
because I think we're both on this
program it's a private program so I
won't say who it is but uh the mobile
app was primarily in scope and I was
looking at the mobile app and there was
some interesting functionality uh in one
of the API
endpoint responses and there was like a
Json object that had a bunch of
different configurations URLs and stuff
in it and one of them was a DOT HTML
file which kind of caught my eye because
like a lot of times in modern web app
infrastructure you really don't see like
raw.html like that
um and it just seemed like a kind of a
weird endpoint I was like huh like I
wonder what that is and so I like I went
to it and it rendered like some very
strange stuff and there was like this
login functionality we're supposed to
like log in so it can get your account
and then you can uh do you know app
functionality to
schedule something is what I'll say
um and so I was like poking at it and I
was like huh this is really weird but I
wonder
like if this is actually being used
because every time I would try and
Export it like I would click login and
it would send me to a different page I
was like huh this is like this is kind
of weird uh maybe you know maybe this is
just like a Dev environment or something
so I go I log in and I it takes me to
like the main page and I notice like
very very similar to The Dot HTML that I
was looking at embedded within the page
I was like huh okay so I look and it's
an iframe
um and it's it's an iframe from a
different URL but it's rendering
essentially the same thing as that dot
HTML and so as I kept digging uh I
realized that it does post-message
Communications to talk back and forth
because it's embedded within an iframe
it has to pass authentication from the
main site into decipherit and so I was
like huh I wonder how that works like
how is it like what's actually
triggering that to you know send over
the off like is it a certain event like
what are the restrictions on that could
I put my own frame in there like
whatever so I start digging and sure
enough there's I mean the Stars really
aligned on this one because there's this
functionality for different environments
within this iframe and essentially it
has a URL parameter called override URL
and essentially it checks for you know
it's supposed to be that if you if you
set it to local then it like uses 127.00
or something right sure but they had you
know they essentially didn't check if it
was you know that you could you could
put whatever you wanted in there like if
it was just like you know
if it's not in the URL and it just
defaults to whatever you've set it to
and so I could just set it to my own
iframe and then it would embed my iframe
in the page and so then I could send a
post message a webview in the mobile app
or is this in in like on web no so
that's the weird thing is like it
started out from the mobile app and then
it ended up just being a complete web
bug like it I only found that URL and
the fact that it was I've rained and all
that from the config endpoint within
that mobile app and then all I and then
I realized oh this is like on the main
site it's like a different URL but the
functionality is all the same
interesting um so yeah I could set uh
this parameter to my own URL it would
then set the iframe source to that URL
put it in the page and then you could
send post messages to the parent and
there's all these different like
commands and stuff so initially I just
wow you know I sent the one it sent
sends me the auth token I was like okay
that's pretty cool and then I kept
poking and I was like oh there's
actually like a lot more functionality
in here and so you could do all sorts of
things like you could um you could it's
ridiculous there was actually one action
called go to and it would just do
window.location equals whatever so you
could just relax yeah a second yeah
basically second exercise
um you could get geolocation through one
of the other actions there was like a
lot of really interesting functionality
but it all just stemmed from this random
you know URL that I was like I wonder
what that is and then when I was trying
to log in with it I realized that it was
sending me back to the main page and it
was you know doing very very similar
functionality but from a different URL
and uh the team actually accepted it
which is which is amazing that is cool
technically I think it was probably
would have been out of scope according
to the explicit scope that was written
down but it's on the main website and
it's
as well so right yeah so that was a oh
and I'm looking right now and it seems
that they actually added they added the
the main site to the scope yeah
so we need to go check that uh yeah yeah
that was a that was a really fun one
um I've actually been enjoying hacking
on this program you know the one I'm
talking about but uh yeah they have uh
they have a pretty cool scope and it's
something that I use person so after the
live hacking event in in Japan so yeah
yeah for sure I love post message bugs
post message bugs are so much fun I see
we talk about them all the time on the
Pod but they're essentially apis for
your your you know browser tabs
essentially yeah
um and why would you not want to
remotely interact with a browser tab
um yes exactly very very cool stuff
there
um yeah alrighty my report for the day
is uh also a private program so I can't
really talk about it but uh I can tell
you the gist of it
and uh I will say that this uh chain
starts with a xss uh and it came from
none other than Mr today's new himself
Eric so thank you for that thanks for
the assist there Eric
um and I found this whole whole chain
and I had an exercise that had already
been reported that I used to explain the
first time they were like dupe because
uh you know you you already use the
exercise and you can't use it in another
ATO chain and I was like guys you're
literally putting your users at so much
risk right now by not missing this I
guarantee you there's another uh you
know another exercise on your attack
surface right now that could be used to
escalate this they didn't accept it
there we go couple couple weeks later we
do uh we do another
um
we do another run of it and uh find an
xss uh yeah Eric Eric finds it in his
automation passes it over to me and uh
we we exploit the bug so here's how it
works
um essentially what it is is it's taking
advantage of uh sort of a session
fixation but for the password reset
um and so what what you can do is you
can use nxs on star.anything and you can
take a a specific session that you can
generate and stick it in a cookie and
set that cookie to a very specific scope
okay to the specific path so um the way
that cookies work in the browser if you
put a cookie at a more specific path
then another cookie even if the domain
is wider that that cookie will be
prioritized when it is sent to the
server so
um let's say you have two cookies with
the name uh you know session right if if
the path that you're on is slash login
and one of the cookies is set to slash
login and one of the cookies set to
slash the slash login will be sent first
and oftentimes prioritize and you're
saying even if the cookie that's scoped
for slash login is set to the Stars even
even if it's like specific
subdomain.host.com it'll still override
I believe so yes um okay and so uh the
only
you know I'm actually wondering now
whether both of them have to be set to
the star scope right or to like dot
site.com or whether that's interesting
I'll have to check that but I know for a
fact that if both of them are set to dot
site.com then the one with that with the
more specific path will be set first
and so in that sort of way we can uh get
our cookie to Pro be prioritized so then
another trick that we can do is we
password or we cookie bomb the password
reset
um
the password reset flow
um or the uh the login flow excuse me
and when they go to log in if you Cookie
bomb that specific path then the request
will fail okay and uh because the header
size is inflated because of all the
cookies you sent from the other
subdomain okay then when the request
fails it just gives you an invalid
password uh response
um and so what they're what are they
going to do if they're going to reset
their password
um so they go to the password reset flow
they they start going through the flow
and uh when they get to the end of the
flow there's a screen where you can set
a new a new password
uh this whole time they've been using
our maliciously set password reset token
um okay and at that point we uh use that
password reset uh session to go directly
to that page and then reset the password
before they can set the password
um and then we take over the account uh
and super interesting that is the that
is the account takeover that uses a
um a cookie prioritization trick uh
cookie bombing and uh sort of a session
fixation bug
so how did how did the program in triage
react because that's kind of like
did it automatically take them to the
password reset flow if it failed uh when
you Cookie bombed it or
no like during login or no okay I they
they accepted the attack scenario that
if you could figure out a way to tell
the pat user that their password is
wrong every single time they try to log
in that the next logical step would be
to reset their password
um okay so yeah so it's essentially a
Dos that leads them to you know reset
their password so they can log in
because it's saying invalid password or
whatever login failed exactly because
because the login request fails every
time because of the the uh
and then uh the password reset flow uh
they they go down that path and then
we've fixated the session for that
so super cool that's a super dope bug
pretty fun bug right
yeah that's awesome that's that's a
really interesting one I'm gonna have to
to look for stuff like that I almost
never look for like cookie bombing stuff
because it really it's so Case by case
but that's a really good instance of it
yeah cookie stuff this is another thing
that they sort of came to mind when you
were talking earlier about what kind of
things you
um you look for particularly when you uh
are starting assessing a program for me
I always look at the cookies and I look
at the authorization
um headers and and any sort of cool
codes that are being thrown around from
an oauth flow or anything like that
um it's very important especially on
those websites where you got like 50
bajillion cookies that are being sent
and you don't know which one's the
session token you don't know which one
is like sort of your elevated session
token you don't know which one like
tells whether you're not used to
remember the username you know there's
just so many so many cookies out there
and they all just kind of get
conglomerated together and so I will
give another shout out to something I
gave a brief shout out to in the past on
critical thinking um and that is the
groups we plug in called request
minimizer this is safety this is
something I yeah this is something that
I actually do I I wasn't gonna I wasn't
sure if other people do this and I think
yeah I think we've talked about this but
I if I'm you know messing with a request
and there's a ton of cookies like that
one of the first things I will do is
I'll go I'll open the request inspector
on burp and I'll do this manually I'll
just go like open the cookies I'll
select like 80 of them and I'll just
delete it and then I'll just send the
request and if it succeeds then I'll do
a binary search right exactly and and if
it fails after the first time then I
know that the cookie that I need is in
there and so then I delete all the other
ones and then if it's still delete the
other ones yeah two cookies so yeah
that's kind of what I do but there's a
there's an extension for this you're
saying
yeah there's an extension for this
called request minimizer and essentially
what it does is it just tries to remove
everything you possibly can from the
request
um and still get the same response
um and I use this plugin all the time
really valuable for analyzing what
exactly is important in an HTTP request
so I definitely recommend it
that's awesome yeah I'm gonna have to um
I'm gonna have to grab this for my for
my very cool
dude I think uh I think that's it I
think that's a wrap yeah
yeah I think that's that's pretty much
it uh good little chat get back to life
hacking and all that kind of stuff try
to get some sleep before your flight
is it uh is it a direct for you from
from Virginia yeah for sure man I uh
no no it's a it's a one little one one
hop up to DC and then a direct to hanada
um so yeah not too bad I think it's like
15 hours or 16 hours total not not too
bad
[Music]
um okay 15 hours
yeah I land today for you so okay yeah
sweet all right well I'll see you uh
tonight then I guess no no no no no no
no no no I land tomorrow for you
because I lose time going to Japan I'll
see you tomorrow all right peace
peace out
foreign